Matthew Jacobson

matthew.g.jacobson@gmail.com (303) 217-0711

www.iammattjacobson.com New York, NY

SUMMARY

Statistician/Data Engineer with 8+ years of experience in predictive modeling, data analytics and reporting, building data intensive cloud based applications, and tackling challenging problems in Marketing and Finance. Currently helping LiftLab build an automated A/B testing platform for Marketers.

EDUCATION

EXPERIENCE

Senior Engineer @ LiftLab May 2018 - Present

- Expanded skills with scalable cloud computing: S3, EC2, EMR, Lambda, Redshift.
- Designed and developed easily consumable REST APIs for internal consumption.
- Provided AdWords API expertise and managed a team developing for the platform.
- Designed and developed complex algorithms for identity resolution in Spark GraphX.

Senior Statistician @ Neustar Dec 2015 - Feb 2018

- Led exploratory data analyses and predictive modeling efforts across multiple clients.
- Automated common reporting tasks across the modeling team.
- Worked with data engineering team to streamline ETL processes.
- Delivered client facing methodology presentations.

Manager, Data Strategy @ MarketShare Apr 2015 - Dec 2015

- Designed and developed ETL processes capturing key business requirements.
- Worked closely with modeling teams to identify and translate new findings into insights.
- Utilized various visualization tools to review data with clients and statisticians.

Business Consultant @ DataSong Jun 2014 - Apr 2015

- Met with clients to identify business needs and analytic objectives.
- Designed and executed high impact solutions delivering key business insights.
- Interpreted analytical results and established next steps with clients.

Decision Science Analyst @ SquareTwo Financial May 2012 - Jun 2014

- Developed skills in database manipulation, statistical modeling, and ad hoc reporting.
- Responsible for cleaning raw data files and exploratory data analysis exercises.
- Assisted in statistical risk valuation exercises and KPI creation and validation.

SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, C++, JavaScript, Scala, SAS, R, Bash, VBA Databases: SQL, PostgreSQL, MapReduce, Hadoop, Hive Cloud Computing: AWS, S3, Lambda, Redshift, RDS, Athena, EC2, EMR Frameworks: Spark, GraphX, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, RunwayML

EXTRA

- As a student in the Fall 2017 cohort at the School for Poetic Computation I focused on exploring the intersections of code, design, hardware and theory focusing especially on artistic intervention.
- As a teaching assistant at the School for Poetic Computation for the Spring 2018, Fall 2018, and Spring 2019 cohorts I helped lead a class called Recreating the Past in which we studied computational art from the past and recreated them with contemporary techniques to gain aesthetic, analytical, and technical knowledge.
- As an adjunct professor at Parsons School of Design from Fall 2019 through Spring 2020 I taught two classes: Creative Computing and Core Lab Interaction. Both introduce students to programming as a creative medium and focus on developing a vocabulary of interaction design principles which can then be applied across a range of platforms.